Geimssy Bermudez

Táchira, Venezuela geimssy.alejandro@gmail.com +584247262669

Summary

Achievement-oriented freelance translator, editor and proofreader of general and tech-related texts with experience using CAT tools, translation memories and linguistic corpora. Dependable sales representative with 3 years of experience in inside and in-person sales providing excellent customer service.

Experience

Atypical Man

Sales Representative/Marketing • Toronto, Ontario

05/2022 - 03/2023

- Managed the company's Instagram accounts with a combined 10000+ organic followers.
- Responsible for outbound sales and cold texting potential customers.
- Responsible for Instagram lead generation, resulting in new sales opportunities every week.
- Accurately guided customers through orders, and resolved any issues during order fulfillment, leading to an increase in sales and tips.
- Addressed lead generation issues, leading to an improvement in customer leads.
- Built rapport with clients by providing quality customer service, leading to an increase in engagement and sales.
- Established personal connections with customers, exceeding customer service expectations.
- Wrote a daily sales report and provided daily feedback on the brand's Instagram accounts performance.
- Maintained an active outreach schedule, talking to over 50 different potential new customers, as well as past customers, per day.
- Used Google Sheets to track sales process metrics.
- Took over the marketing side of the accounts, leading to a change in the overall Instagram accounts' aesthetics.
- Was in charge of editing and posting photos sent by customers to fit the brand's aesthetic.

Exquisita Alma de Mujer

Salesperson/Customer Service

01/2020 - 04/2022

- Responsible for interacting with customers and selling items at the store, meeting a daily sales quota.
- Provided successful and personalized customer service, resulting in a 100% retention rate of past customers.

Upwork

Freelance Translator 03/2017 - 03/2019

- 100.919 translated words (Spanish into English) in the field of technology.
- Little experience localizing games and apps found in the Google Play Store.
- Used computer-assisted translation (CAT) tools, including MemoQ and OmegaT, to verify consistency within documents and improve efficiency, and compiled technological terms to create a personal terminology database, resulting in a smoother translation process.

PandaGossips

Freelance Proofreader 09/2017 - 04/2018

• Revised and edited general articles written in English prior to their publication on the site, resulting in error-free and high quality texts.

• Communicated with writers to provide feedback about their work, leading to a better long-term workflow.

Freelance Interpreter

Interpreter English/Spanish

- 04/2017 12/2017
- Provided simultaneous interpretation (English Spanish) during a 3-day event that gathered Japanese and Venezuelan businessmen, allowing the event to take place effectively.
- Provided consecutive interpretation (English Spanish) for Canadian and Venezuelan firemen during a knowledge exchange event as a volunteer for the University of Los Andes' Translation Service, resulting in a successful experience for both parties.

Fundaldiomas

English Language Instructor

09/2016 - 03/2017

- Taught English to teenagers and adults using creative methods to improve their learning process, resulting in a 100% success rate.
- Assessed students' abilities and grasp of the English language, providing feedback to work on their weaknesses.
- â—

 Kept records and prepared progress reports to assess the students' progression.
- Implemented a hands-on approach to learning, resulting in an improvement in the students' performance across the board.

Education

University of Los Andes

Bachelor's Degree in Modern Languages

12/2019

- Minored in Translation.
- · Graduated magna cum laude.
- Coursework in Linguistics (phonetics, phonology, morphology, syntax, semantics, and pragmatics), Culture,
 Literature and Translation.
- Awarded a commendation for publication for my thesis, which was a translation commentary of a master's thesis in Gender Studies at Utrecht University.

Languages

Spanish, English, French

Skills

Editing, Proofreading, Customer service, Communication skills, Computer literacy, Computer skills, Interpersonal skills, Collaboration, Attention to detail, Research